JANET OGENYI

FRONTEND ENGINEER

Lagos, Nigeria

08164400387

janeteneogenyi@gmail.com | Github | LinkedIn

PROFILE SUMMARY

I transform ideas into functional interfaces while prioritizing accessibility and aesthetics. Dedicated Frontend Engineer with a strong commitment to crafting inclusive user experiences from design concepts.

I also love contributing to thee open-source community, where I collaborate on projects that drive innovation and accessibility in the tech ecosystem. I flourish in environments that encourage autonomy and foster personal and professional growth.

SKILLS

Reactjs | Nextjs | Typescript | Storybook | Redux | React Query | TailwindCSS | SCSS | SASS | Context API | Chakra UI | Styled Components | Unit testing | REST API | Tanstack-query | Javascript | Agile Methodologies | Teamwork | JIRA | GIT & Github | Wordpress CMS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer

May 2021 - Present

Truparse

- Revamped the company's website to the new version.
- Built and successfully launched the company's digital platform "Figur", a fintech app used by over 5000 users and designed to empower individuals and businesses in efficiently managing their accounts.
- Build and maintain an internal dispute resolution portal (admin dashboard) used by the team for customer resolutions.
- Built the Figur blog pages.

Frontend Engineer

March 2022 - Oct 2022

Viwlo

- Developed independent, reusable, and responsive React components with a design system in a component library using Storybook.
- Implemented unit testing, which covers most of the positive flows in the app, which has now given us more confidence to release new features.

PROJECTS

Figur Africa: https://figur.africa/

A Fintech web app built for individuals and businesses to experience seamless accessibility to pay bills effortlessly, Open active personal & business accounts, receive and withdraw money.

Nigerian Constitution Website: https://hccr.gov.ng/

The official Nigerian constitution website - built for the House of Representatives Committee on the Review of the Constitution of the Federal Republic of Nigeria

Job Lynk: https://job-lynk.com/

A web app that helps users land their perfect job. Connect with top employers and get hired for the their desired jobs.

Figur Admin Dashboard

Admin Dashboard for Figur Africa; a Fintech web app built for individuals and businesses to experience seamless accessibility to pay bills effortlessly, Open active personal & business accounts, receive and withdraw money.

Job Lynk Admin Dashboard

Admin Dashboard for Job Lynk; a web app that helps users land their perfect job. Connect with top employers and get hired for the their desired jobs.

Nipost Admin Dashboard

Admin dashboard for the Nigerian Postal Service

VOLUNTEERING

August 2023

Open source contributor

Infisical

• Collaborated with the CTO and other developers to fix some bugs and implement new feautures on the Infisical app.

EDUCATION 2014 - 2018

Bachelor's Degree, Chemistry

Benue State University